Hadi Gunawan

hadigunawan987@gmail.com | +6285781722743 | South Tangerang, Banten 15424 | linkedin.com/in/hadi-gunawan-875889199/ | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering from Pamulang University, I have work experience for approximately 2 years. I have an enthusiasm to work in the data science fields for instance: Jr/Entry level Data Analyst, Business Intelligence, etc, but do not rule out opportunities in other fields. Eager to learn and adapt to a new team and company.

EXPERIENCE

Retention and Winback, Myrepublic ID

Aug 2018 - July 2020

- Make outbound calls to customers who have a tendency to churn/move to other competitors in order to minimize the occurrence of churn (customer and target-oriented)
- Keeping touch with customers by escalating reports related to customer problems and rewards to customers. Using google sheets, CRM and tools for instance: Zendesk, internal CRM, Hermes
- Successfully achieve 100% of KPI every month or even more.

Data Entry (Vocational School Internship), BP2T South Tangerang

Jan 2016 - Feb 2016

- Entry data into Microsoft Excel, organize physical data into the warehouse, and maintaining them
- Overall got a grade A result.

LICENSE AND CERTIFICATIONS

SQL Fundamentals Track (DataCamp)

Learning and practicing about Structured Query Language (SQL), in this course I learning from basic to intermediate, window function, correlated queries, nested queries, Common Table Expressions (CTE), built-in PostgreSQL functions and many more

Python Fundamentals Track (DataCamp)

Learning and practicing about python from basic (Data Analysis, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)), learn some packages/libraries such as: Pandas, Matplotlib (Data Visualization), and NumPy

Tableau Fundamentals Track (DataCamp)

Learning and practicing about data preparation, data interpretation, identification, data visualization, getting insight from data, building dashboard, make a storytelling of data using Tableau.

And many more..

SKILLS

Hard Skills and Tools: Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Interpretation, Data Visualization, Build Dashboard, Ms.Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint), SQL, Tableau, Power Bi, Google Sheets, Google Data Studio, HTML, CSS, Github, MySQL, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq, VSCode, (Novice: SQL Server, PHP, Python, Flutter, AWS) Soft Skills: Communication, Critical Thinking, Teamwork, Adaptability, Problem-Solving, Collaboration.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering (Computer Science) **Pamulang University**

Sept 2017 – Dec 2021 GPA: 3.46/4.00

Relevant coursework: Database, Algorithms and Programming, Data Communication, Statistics, Informatics Logic, Calculus, Basic Physics, Computer Programming, Data Structures, AI, DSS.